[
    {
        "question": "In which city does the Ponte Vecchio span the Arno river?",
        "answer": "Florence"
    },
    {
        "question": "Niamey is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Niger"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which African country celebrates its gorillas with an annual naming ceremony?",
        "answer": "Rwanda -- Kwita Izina is an annual naming ceremony in Rwanda for baby mountain gorillas born in the past year."
    },
    {
        "question": "Kinyarwanda is the official language of what nation?",
        "answer": "Rwanda"
    },
    {
        "question": "The annual `Christmas Book Flood` is part of what country`s holiday tradition?",
        "answer": "Iceland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country does the island of Guernsey belong to?",
        "answer": "United Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which European country would you find the town of Eupen?",
        "answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which region of France do Germans call Lothringen?",
        "answer": "Lorraine"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the `Land of 10,000 Lakes`?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river flows along the southern border of South Carolina?",
        "answer": "Savannah River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which holiday inspired Florida`s official name?",
        "answer": "Juan Ponce de Leon named the state after his home country`s Easter celebration: Pascua Florida, which means feast of flowers."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the first European name for Hawaii?",
        "answer": "Captain James Cook, the first European to visit the islands, named them `the Sandwich islands` to honor the Earl of Sandwich."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was an alternative name for Maryland?",
        "answer": "Mariana (Lord Baltimore squashed the idea because the name reminded him of Spanish Jesuit and historian Juan de Mariana.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which natural feature is Michigan named after?",
        "answer": "Lake (The word `Michigan` is a French derivative of the Ojibwa word `misshikama,` which means `large lake` or `large water`.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sculptor Gutzon Borglum created the the design for what national monument in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "Mount Rushmore"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the Canadian province of Manitoba?",
        "answer": "Winnipeg"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many independent city-states were there in the world in 2020?",
        "answer": "Three"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Libya?",
        "answer": "Tripoli"
    },
    {
        "question": "Parma and Tuscany are regions of what country?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Including maritime borders, which country shares borders with China, US, Finland and Ukraine?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What mountain overlooks Cape Town, South Africa?",
        "answer": "Table Mountain"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which river runs through Paris?",
        "answer": "Seine"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Hollywood Walk of Fame is located along what street?",
        "answer": "Hollywood Boulevard"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the five Great Lakes?",
        "answer": "Superior, Michigan, Huron, Erie and Ontario"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whidbey Island is the largest island in which state?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "question": "Columbia University is located in which US city?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is the capital of the US state Arkansas?",
        "answer": "Little Rock"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the Mayflower land in New England in 1620?",
        "answer": "Cape Cod - The Mayflower sailed from England to the \u201cNew World,\u201d landing in Plymouth Harbor along the shores of Cape Cod."
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the city of Regina, Saskatchewan named for?",
        "answer": "Queen Victoria - Originally a hunters` camp named Pile O`Bones, the settlement was renamed Regina, Latin for `queen`."
    },
    {
        "question": "What strategically important island is part of the Hawaiian archipelago, but not the state of Hawaii?",
        "answer": "Midway Atoll -- It`s instead a U.S. territory that is part of the U.S. Minor Outlying Islands. It was annexed in 1867."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s largest greenhouse?",
        "answer": "Cornwall, England -- The Eden Project is home to more than one million plants. It features two hexagonally-patterned biomes."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two countries does The Netherlands border?",
        "answer": "Belgium and Germany"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state is the source of the Arkansas, Platte, and Rio Grande rivers?",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Gadsden Purchase involved the lower portions of what are now which two US states?",
        "answer": "Arizona and New Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "What state is nicknamed the `Beehive State`?",
        "answer": "Utah"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Arizona?",
        "answer": "Phoenix"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to Lassen Volcano National Park?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does Salzburg translate to?",
        "answer": "Salt Castle"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Grand National horse race held?",
        "answer": "Liverpool, England"
    },
    {
        "question": "The majority of the Sierra Nevada Mountains are located in which state?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mouth of the Mississippi River is located in which state?",
        "answer": "Louisiana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is the capital of the US state Idaho?",
        "answer": "Boise"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Ivy League school is located in Ithaca?",
        "answer": "Cornell University"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to Newberry National Volcanic Monument?",
        "answer": "Oregon"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is directly south of Virginia?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to Hot Springs National Park?",
        "answer": "Arkansas"
    },
    {
        "question": "What U.S. state capital city is located at the southern shores of Lake Oahe?",
        "answer": "Pierre"
    },
    {
        "question": "What islands were purchased by the US from Denmark in 1916?",
        "answer": "US Virgin Islands"
    },
    {
        "question": "What four countries share land borders with Montenegro?",
        "answer": "Croatia, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Serbia and Albania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Montenegro`s coastline lies on which sea?",
        "answer": "Adriatic Sea"
    }
]